TRICIA NORRIS, MBA, CSPO, CSM

5816 E Rois Rd. | Richmond, VA 23227 (804) 614-6547 tricianorris97@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/tricianorris
Github: https://github.com/plnorris97
Portfolio: https://plnorris97/github.io

Professional Summary

Beginning web designer and developer currently attending UR Coding Bootcamp, a full stack web development certificate. I am also a marketing professional with over 18 years of experience in digital marketing, web strategy, project management, email marketing and marketing collateral creation. Proficient in collaborating with project stakeholders, vendors and clients. Focused on constant improvement and professional development.

Professional Experience

Talking Monkey Media

July 2018-Present

Marketing Manager

- Manage relationships with small business and non-profit clients
- Provide project management for website clients coordinating between designers and developers
- Direct and manage social media campaigns including planning, scheduling, designing social media brand

Norris Consulting, LLC March 2016-Present

Principal, Head Marketer

- Connect small businesses with creatives resources
- Provide marketing project management support for new and existing marketing plans
- Build comprehensive, multi-channel strategies using digital, traditional and inbound tactics

Capital One (Profiles)

June 29, 2016-December 2017

Marketing Manager

- Develop and implement annual strategies for trade show and sales channels
- Manage team projects in a cross-functional agile environment
- Refine existing processes with other functional teams
- Partner with Affiliates client development team to identify synergies in strategy and execution

Genworth Financial

December 2011-April 2016

Marketing Specialist

- Supported the life and annuity product lines for 25 internal/external wholesalers & 12 individual products
- Led improvement of relationship between Marketing and Web teams between 2014 and 2015, reducing turnaround from 1-2 weeks to 1-3 days
- Product owner/web content manager for 4 producer and consumer websites
- Launched The Index Institute (2014-2015) while collaborating with teams of developers, UX, design, research, analytics and stakeholders; project was total rework of 73 components and pages; illustration exits increased by 77%; file downloads increased 5%; time spent on site increased 3%
- Launched The LTC Source (2015) while collaborating with teams of developers, UX, design, research, analytics and stakeholders; project was total rework of 86 components and pages
- Maintained website backlogs (~10 active items/month) and test plans for iteration on web properties
- Managed website monthly subscription email sent to members; increased email click-to-open rate by 7.4% (2015 vs. 2014)
- Assisted in day to day management of Edward Jones annuity relationship (2011-2015)

Genworth Financial

November 2010-December 2011

Premier Partners Sales Associate (Retail)

- Provided pre-sales and marketing support to Retail long term care, life and annuity Agents in San
 Francisco, Los Angeles and San Diego
- Assisted Agents with marketing needs by identifying concepts, sales strategies and fulfillment
- Coordinated Agent drip campaigns targeting clients, prospects and Centers of Influence

Headway Corporate Resources-Genworth

January 2010 – November 2010

Long Term Care Marketing Specialist

- Supported the LTC product line and delivered core marketing & sales concepts to a 20-person Sales team
- Managed 300+ recomply sales pieces in project workflow tool while collaborating with Marketing team
- Maintained inventory of current marketing materials
- Assisted in day to day management of the Edward Jones LTC relationship

Rightminds

November 2009-January 2010

Account Coordinator-Web

- Assisted with account management of new media clients including website user experience and maintenance as well as client communication
- Supported other agency functions as necessary in graphics and art department

SunTrust Bank – Mid Atlantic

September 2008-June 2009

Group Marketing Associate-Events and Sponsorships Coordinator

- Fulfilled sponsorship requests in the Mid Atlantic footprint managing contract review, renewal and budget
- Team lead for activating selected sponsorships, fulfilling all deliverables from business strategy to onsite tactical implementation
- Identified efficiencies within event categories to improve activation expenses and look for synergies across the Mid Atlantic Group
- Provided post event ROI analysis to maximize business generation, retention and potential relationship expansion
- Maintained inventory of promotional items, banners and signage for use during events

EDUCATION

- Professional Certificate Full Stack Web Development, '19 University of Richmond
- Masters of Business Administration '14 Virginia Commonwealth University
- Bachelor of Arts, Spanish and International Studies (Latin America) '97 Elon University
- Study Abroad: Ecuador (Spring '97) Costa Rica (Winter '95)

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified Scrum Product Owner® '15, ScrumAlliance.org, Lic. 512888
- Certified Scrum Master, '16, ScrumAlliance.org, Lic. 582143
- Certified Direct Marketer, Interactive Marketing Institute, '08

AWARDS

- Marketing Automation, Genworth, '12
- Three Point Star Award for Commitment to Superior Service, LandAmerica '06

EXPERTISE & SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Moment.js, Github, Agile Scrum, Project Management, Digital Marketing, Adobe CQ5, Web Analytics/ Reporting, Adobe Marketing Cloud, Web Strategy, Content Marketing, Social Media Marketing, Photoshop CC, Email Marketing, Oracle® Eloqua, Paid Advertising, Wordpress